Contact

dhbucher@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/donaldbucher-dnp-acnp-bc-43b38761 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

ACLS

Acute Care

Critical Care

Certifications

CCRN

CRNP

ACNP-BC

Publications

Implementation of an evidencebased blood transfusion education program in the intensive care unit: Evaluating nursing knowledge and impacting best practice

Implementation of an Intensive Care Unit Delirium Protocol: An Interdisciplinary Quality Improvement Project

Propofol infusion syndrome: A rare complication with potentially fatal results

Donald Bucher DNP, ACNP-BC

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner

Harrisburg, Pennsylvania

Summary

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner with 12 years of Hosptialist and Critical Care experience. Prior ICU RN, leader and educator. "Never lose sight of the fact that the most important yardstick of your success will be how you treat other people — your family, friends, and coworkers, and even strangers you meet along the way," Bush

Experience

Pennsylvania College of Health Sciences Assistant Professor March 2020 - Present (4 months)

Sound Physicians
Acute Care Nurse Practitioner
August 2019 - Present (11 months)

DHB-NP Services LLC

Owner

January 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Provide Consulting, Contracted services in healthcare and medical chart review

Medicus Healthcare Solutions Hospitalist Nurse Practitioner March 2017 - Present (3 years 4 months)

Penn State Health Acute Care Nurse Practitioner June 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 7 months) Hershey, Pennsylvania

Moravian College Assistant Professor 2018 - August 2019 (1 year) Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

Matrix Medical Network

Nurse Practitioner

October 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Pulmonary & Critical Care Medicine Associates Acute Care Nurse Practitioner December 2015 - March 2017 (1 year 4 months) Harrisburg, Pennsylvania Area

Pinnacle Health Management Acute Care Nurse Practitioner August 2015 - December 2015 (5 months)

Harrisburg, Pennsylvania

Clinically provides and manages health care of acutely ill, critically ill, and chronically ill adult patients in a wide range of clinical settings within the medical center. Performs physical exams, collects and documents data, conducts approved diagnostic and therapeutic procedures, orders and schedules laboratory studies and professional consultations, prescribes appropriate interventions and medications, and provides direct patient care services in a specific ICU. Performed advanced procedures including CVC, Arterial line, and endotracheal intubations. Served as a preceptor for new nurse practitioners and nurse practitioner students. Mentor new providers in ICU.

UPMC Hamot

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner August 2007 - August 2015 (8 years 1 month)

Provide leadership and oversight to the Advance Practice Providers for the Hospitalist, Critical care and Palliative Care.

Developed schedule, clinical structure and policies for the new advanced practice program in critical care at UPMC Hamot.

Clinically provides and manages health care of acutely ill, critically ill, and chronically ill adult patients in a wide range of clinical settings within the medical center. Performs physical exams, collects and documents data, conducts approved diagnostic and therapeutic procedures, orders and schedules laboratory studies and professional consultations, prescribes appropriate interventions and medications, and provides direct patient care services in a specific ICU. Performed advanced procedures including CVC,

Arterial line, and endotracheal intubations. Served as a preceptor for new nurse practitioners and nurse practitioner students. Mentor new providers in ICU.

Education

Chatham University

DNP, Doctorate of Nursing Practice · (2010 - 2011)

University of Pittsburgh - School of Nursing

Master's of Nursing, Acute Care Nurse Practitioner · (2005 - 2007)

Pennsylvania State University-Penn State Shenango Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1999 - 2000)

Sharon Regional Health System School of Nursing
Diploma, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1994 - 1998)